Amresha Soomro

Accomplished Senior Technical Project Manager offering 10 years of experience in Software Project Management. Successful when leading high-performing teams to sustain product vision, roadmap and business goals. Exceptional technical expertise, leadership and talent for driving stellar, on-target results.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SEPA Cyber Technologies, Istanbul — Senior Technical Project Manager

FEB 2023 - Present

- Full project life cycle ownership: successful project delivery including full implementation from initiation to LIVE deployment for 8 different EU and UK client base offering digital banking features
- Prepare estimates and detailed project plan for all phases of the project that also includes determining and defining clear deliverables, roles and responsibilities for each staff member required for a specific project
- Lead Global team of 7 front-end, 23 back-end developers, 5 Mobile developers, 5 QAs performance and assess monthly tasks completion by each team
- Closely monitor and supervise QA checks for the deployed projects and manage defects resolution
- Weekly coordinate with around 8 external vendors from the EU region to make sure all required APIs are consistent as per the internal project module requirements.
- Timely measure deployment efforts for both Beta and Live Env
- Circulate Monthly Dashboard of Project Progress to C-Level

SEPA Cyber Technologies, Istanbul — IT Project Manager

FEB 2022 - Feb 2023

- Plan, implement, coordinate and oversee large-scale Southern European Digital Banking Solution as a Whitelabel product for various different clients from UK and Europe
- Main responsibilities include coordinating production releases and roll-outs, delegate tasks to the relevant available IT resources, schedule regular production tests, and present on projects' progress and results to the clients
- Coordinating with the on-board vendors and organizing calls with the backend developers for API integration, some of the core banking APIs were related to KYC, KYB, PEP-Sanctions, IPG and Bank Transfer operations.

CONTACT

Address: Istanbul, Turkey Phone: (+90) 5013297422 Email: amreshabux@gmail.com

HIGHLIGHTS

Strong knowledge of SDLC and Agile methodologies.

End-to-end project management of 8 in-house bank's web applications.

MERN Stack, REST services & API integration

SOFT SKILLS

Excellent Analytical, Communication and Coaching skills

Effective Team building, Supervision and Project Management skills

Talent Evaluation/Screening for hiring digital Tech staff

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced MS Office, JIRA,

Web Technologies hands-on experience: HTML5/CSS3, ReactJS, GatsbyJS & Bootstrap Framework, NodeJS, Express, GitHub, NPM, Webpack, Babel, AWS, WordPress & WooCommerce, Headless CMSs

Fiver, Istanbul — Freelance Front-End Engineer

AUG 2020 - JAN 2022

 Managed the US and European based clients, the project scope was to build a front-end and back-end from scratch using the latest modern web development technology i.e ReactJS and headless CMS, migrate existing content and website deployment on Github repository & deployment on Netlify Server.

US Clients: https://www.austinaccidentlawyer.com

EU Client: https://geneesiezelf.nu/

Ata Kurumsal, Istanbul — Digital Project Manager

NOV 2018 - JUL 2020

- Supervised digital design and development team of 3 employees
- Used Trello as an agile project management tool
- Managed the company's existing WordPress web portfolio also proposed transformation of 2 slow WordPress multilingual websites to blazingly fast ReactJS powered websites that boosted page load speed to up to 95% and eventually increased lead generation.
- Reorganized development staff as well as technical resources for ongoing projects.

Self-Employed, Karachi — *Graphic Designer/ Web Developer*

JAN 2013 - AUG 2018

 Designed and Developed eCommerce & CMS Web Application for various USA and UAE based clients related to Cosmetics, Apparels, Cutlery, Legal firms and Corporate firms.

Barclays Bank PLC, Karachi — Fraud Ops & MI Supervisor

MAY 2008 - DEC 2012

- Plan, designed and developed Financial Crime Investigation and Incident Management System
- Supervised design and development team of 2 individuals
- Conducted software training across all front-end branch staff of approximately 25 individuals and 15 back-office staff
- Introduced in-house department Newsletter publication with a monthly dashboard
- Managed VISA, local, EM & Group level regulatory reportings.

United Bank Limited, Karachi — Country MIS Coordinator

AUG 2005 - MAY 2008

- Designed and developed a Case tracking System, Sales Executive tracking and Clearance Sys, Credit Card Issuing and Acquiring System, Fraudulent Customers and Companies database
- Automate department's Financial / Non-Financial Reportings with integrated graphical representation

Database Management & Analytical tools: MS SQL, MS Access, MongoDB, PhpMyAdmin, GraphQL, Tableau, Power BI

Data Science tools: Jupyter, Python and Matlab

AWARD

Barclays Bank PLC 2011 Monthly Spot Award for Exceptional Performance

UBL 2007 Best Performer Award

UBL 2006 Best Performer Award

Informatics 2002 Certificate of Participation In a Software Competition

LANGUAGES

English, Urdu, Sindhi and Turkish

- Conducted countrywide software training of approximately 85 back-office staff and more than 200 front-office branch staff.
- Excellent analytical and insightful analysis on bi-weekly basis for the entire department managed portfolio circulated within EVP level

Glaxo Smith Kline, Karachi — IT Intern

OCT 2003 - NOV 2003

I Had a 6 week's internship experience at GSK (Glaxo Smith Kline)
where I was involved in the designing and documentation of the
software i.e Electronic Central Documentary System' and 'Bill Of
Material' The designing tool that I used was 'Lotus Domino
Designer' I also worked on 'Lotus Notes' and made the presentation
and presented to the 'IT consultant'

EDUCATION

Altinbaş University, Istanbul — *Msc. Data Analytics*

OCT 2024 - In Progress

Altinbaş University, Istanbul — *Msc. IT*

OCT 2022 - JUNE 2024

The master project scope was to detect diabetes using a neural network, my main contribution was to optimize the FeedForward Neural Network model using Artificial Bee Colony Algorithm to obtain high accuracy of upto 99.85%

University of Portsmouth, UK— BSc (Hons) in Computing

OCT 2000 - JUNE 2003

The final project scope was to develop a web-based application for an Ad agency that calculates Ad Space rates based on company-defined parameters.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

Informatics, Karachi — ASP Certificate

JUN 2001 - AUG 2001

Webmaster, Web Project Manager, Web Application Developer

ICT | The Institute of Computer Technology, Karachi— *Diploma in Computer Science*

JUN 1998- JUN 1999

DOS, EDP, Lotus, Windows 95/NT, LAN, Dbase, FoxPro, GW-Basic, Visual Basic 6.0, Word Star, MS Office

REFERENCES References will be furnished on request.